American Society of Adlerian Psychology Records
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
American Society of Adlerian Psychology Records 1951-1970
MSS49361
American Society of Adlerian Psychology
600 items 3 containers 1.2 linear feet
Manuscript Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Society founded in 1951 to foster and promote the work and teachings of Adlerian psychology and its founder, Alfred Adler. Renamed the North American Society of Adlerian Psychology in 1977. Correspondence, minute books, membership lists, and organizational material relating to the history and incorporation of the society.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Adler, Alfred, 1870-1937.
Organizations
American Society of Adlerian Psychology.
Subjects
Adlerian psychology.; Psychology--United States.
Administrative Information
Provenance
The records of the American Society of Adlerian Psychology were given to the Library of Congress by Rowena R. Ansbacher in 1972.
Access and Restrictions
The records of the American Society of Adlerian Pschology are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the American Society of Adlerian Psychology span the years 1951-1970 and consist of correspondence, minute books, membership lists, and organizational material relating to the history and incorporation of an organization founded in 1951 to foster the work and teachings of Adlerian psychology and its founder, Alfred Adler.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is grouped as correspondence, arranged chronologically, followed by other types of material, arranged alphabetically.
http://lccn.loc.gov/mm82049361
Container List
- Correspondence, 1954-1955, (9 folders) (Box 1)
- Articles of incorporation, constitution, bylaws, and amendments, 1954-1965 (Box 1)
- Minutes, reports, and related material, 1953-1966, (2 folders) (Box 2)
- Minute books, 1951-1967, (2 folders) (Box 2)
- Miscellany (Box 3)
  - Alfred Adler Centennial, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Applications, 1954-1966 (Box 3)
  - General, 1954-1970 (Box 3)
  - Home-School Cooperative Education.. ., by Genevieve Painter and Betty Jane Overholt, 1966 (Box 3)
  - International Book List on Individual Psychology, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Membership and other lists, 1954-1966 (Box 3)
  - Press releases, 1964-1966 (Box 3)
  - Printed matter, 1952-1966 (Box 3)